(♪♪♪)
♪ Move on, move ♪
♪ Move on, move,
we're movin' on ♪
♪ Move on, move ♪
♪ Move on Move ♪
♪ We're movin' on ♪
♪ Movin' on, move on ♪
♪ Movin' on ♪
♪ Vente ♪
-(HORN HONKING)
-(SHEEP BLEATING)
-Hello!
-♪ Episcopalis hominem ♪
G'day, mate!
(BIKE BELL RINGS)
♪ Vente ♪
♪ Episcopalis hominem ♪
(SHEEP BLEATING)
(♪♪♪)
(KNOCKER CLAPS)
(DOOR OPENS, CREAKS)
Well... Brian Collins.
What have you done this time?
Blasphemery, Sister.
Blasphemery, eh?
(INHALES)
Well, that's a serious sin--
directly flouting
one of the Ten Commandments.
Dad says
I need a big penance.
What was it that ya said,
exactly?
(MUMBLING):
Jesus Jumping Christ.
-What's that?
-"Jesus Jumping Christ."
You'd better come inside.
♪ Deus meus... ♪
Now, what made you say that?
You see, all day
she stayed, marching around,
using Mum's coffee set
like she owns the place!
Who?
That woman!
Elizabeth Fletcher?
(BRIAN SIGHS)
A lovely girl,
kind enough to help a widower
with five little ones.
You've got a black spot
in your thinking
where Liz is concerned.
You must pray about it.
BRIAN:
Yeah, but now Dad says
us kids can't jump
in the big bed in the morning.
Why not?
Well, 'cause she's in it.
Rumpy pumpy!
(CHUCKLING)
SISTER AGNES:
Sister Mary Clare!
Sister Luke needs her pills.
Brian is looking
to make reparation
for his misuse
of the Holy Name
and uncharitable thoughts
about a certain person.
Serious blasphemery...
-(GASPS)
-...Sister Mary Clare.
I'm thinking
the upstairs floors?
All of them.
♪ Sicut erat in principio ♪
♪ Et nunc, et semper ♪
Why is there so much babies?
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Well, back then,
mummies with babies
and no daddy around,
uh, people... were cruel,
so we would take them in,
look after them.
Agnes used to teach
the little ones.
We were the centre
of this town...
one time.
Then what?
Well, things changed.
They had to.
Mummies could go to work
and earn money.
The town built a school.
We're the last three,
last of the dinosaurs,
but we still
look after our darlings.
(LAUGHS)
Oh! Sister Luke's garden.
She used to tend it
from morning till night.
Not much to look at now.
BRIAN:
I'll say!
Dad says she's 105
and loopy as.
I... meant the garden.
(BOTH SNICKER)
BRIAN:
Mum liked it here.
She said it smells nice.
We loved your mum.
She didn't want to go, Brian.
She tried and tried to stay.
(SCOURS FLOOR)
Yeah, it's not right, I know.
Not fair, is it, Brian Collins?
Why should this be?
"Verily, verily,
I say unto thee,
trust in the Lord,
trust...
and be free!"
BRIAN: Sister Mary Clare!
(SISTER MARY CLARE LAUGHS)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Whee!
Whoo-hoo!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
That was a good one.
(LAUGHING)
Whee!
Faster!
TOGETHER:
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
SISTER LUKE:
Help yourself.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
There, I've
prepared that for you.
Thank you.
Hi, Mum.
♪ Haere mai ♪
♪ Not a cloud in the sky ♪
♪ To coin a phrase ♪
♪ This is the day of days ♪
♪ You're welcome
as the sunshine ♪
as the King ♪
I've done the penance, Mum.
I can come now.
(♪♪♪)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Oh, Agnes.
Please can I go down to him?
SISTER AGNES:
The boy must learn
to go back to his family,
Mary Clare.
Years on,
and he's still no closer
to accepting
his mother's passing.
"Store up the treasures
in Heaven,
but rejoice in your blessings
amongst the living."
Oh--
-Oh. Oh!
-(COUGHING)
(LID RATTLES)
Well...
Now, what is this
about Liz overnighting?
Brian says
she doesn't go home.
Hoo-hoo-hoo! Rumpy pumpy!
(CHUCKLING)
(COUGHING)
Oh!
Oh...
(SISTER LUKE LAUGHS)
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
Have a pill.
Fat lot of good
they're doing.
I'm not fat!
I'm just easy to see.
(SISTER MARY CLARE CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
(♪♪♪)
♪ Joy to the world
the Lord is come ♪
(BRIAN GRUNTS QUIETLY)
LIZ:
Kathy, love,
can you get the chops?
KATHY:
Sure, Liz!
There we go.
And...
bon appétit!
Bless us, dear God,
and these, thy gifts,
which we receive.
The food's getting cold, Brian.
Amen.
-Amen.
LIZ:
Brian, you don't
have any corn.
Here you go.
JOE:
Take the corn.
It's got butter on it!
Oh. Here's a piece.
It's got no butter.
There you go.
(CUTLERY CLATTERS)
JOE:
Brian!
Brian!  I'm sorry, Liz.
(♪♪♪)
WOMAN:
Brian?
(DOOR OPENS, CREAKS)
Come on, mate.
We all miss her.
What you got there?
Mum's mountain.
That's where she came from.
Her people.
Do you see up top,
right up tippy-top?
Mum said that's where...
you step off into forever.
Is it Heaven?
Yeah, maybe.
It's a better place.
Better than
with me and you?
You know, I, um...
I wanted to take you.
Why didn't you?
JOE:
Mummy got sick...
...and then she got better,
then she got sick again.
(SIGHS)
Here. Keep it.
Mummy would like that, yeah?
(♪♪♪)
CHILD:
Can we have
two more stories?
LIZ:
Have you brushed your teeth?
CHILD:
I've already brushed my teeth.
LIZ:
All right, then.
Just one. Maybe two.
Let's see if
Brian wants to join us.
Oh! Brian?
Okay, where were we?
"The secret," she said,
"is courage."
"Only the very brave
will venture into the beyond,
and only the very brave
will be rewarded."
"The climb was steep,
but the boy took it
step by step.
He was cold,
but he knew soon
the sun would come up,
and then he would see."
FATHER FINDLAY:
Oi!
Weren't you here yesterday?
Yeah.
BRIAN:
I've done another sin, Sister!
How many times you been here
in the last few weeks?
I've done
a whole bunch of penances.
♪ Deus meus, ex toto corde ♪
FATHER FINDLAY:
Well, there's a fine thing.
If making reparations
for your sins
was at all important...
...you'd think
you'd remember it, wouldn't ya?
I'll come see you
in your confession hole?
SISTER AGNES:
"Confessional."
Why isn't he at school?
It's holidays.
(SNEEZING)
SISTER AGNES:
Would you like me to fix
a remedy for those sinuses?
Oh, you'll have to watch those.
They don't mix well
with alcohol.
I'll mix you
with alcohol in a minute.
Well... your sin?
I stole. That's a good one.
SISTER AGNES:
"That's a good one"?
Did you?
No. Dad said I could have it.
Would you just like
to help, Brian?
All right.
(♪♪♪)
(SPLUTTERING)
Sister Luke,
Brian would like
to be of assistance.
SISTER LUKE:
Who?
Me! Brian.
What would you like me
to do, Sister?
Well--
(CHUCKLES)
Well, look, he can start...
the door hinge, uh,
probably needs
a bit of attention.
It's very old.
It's all pretty old.
Well, I may be old,
but at least I'm not pregnant.
(LAUGHS)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(CAR DOORS OPENING)
(SISTER AGNES GASPS)
BRIAN: (GASPS)
The Pope!
Bishop.
Chaytor?
The new bishop?
SISTER LUKE:
Icing on the cake, eh?
What does he want?
Hail Mary, full of grace--
SISTER AGNES:
Mary Clare!
Let us prepare for His Grace!
Brian... (SPITS)
...go home.
Wait.
(CLOCK TICKING)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
The tea's gone cold.
I'll make another pot.
SISTER AGNES:
Don't bother, Mary Clare.
They're not coming over.
(SIGHS)
(CAR STARTS)
LIZ:
It's a big step, Joe.
JOE:
Yeah, but the girls
already love you.
LIZ:
I know, but Brian?
JOE:
He'll be fine.
He'll get used to it... to us.
LIZ:
It's not just moving in.
It's the wedding, and--
oh... B-Brian.
What are you doing
with Mum's things?
Sweetheart, y-- your dad and I,
we're just--
We're just, you know,
making a bit of space.
LIZ:
Yeah, we're just
gonna make some changes,
but it's gonna be okay.
These are not your things,
they're my mum's things!
Get out! I don't want you here!
I hate you. Get out!
-Brian...
-Get out! Aah!
-Brian!
BRIAN:
Go away! We don't
need you here! Get out!
JOE:
Hey!
Those are Liz's things.
-LIZ: Brian...
-JOE: Mate... mate...
Hey! Hey, put that back!
Hey, what are you doing?
(DOOR OPENS)
Brian!
(♪♪♪)
(GRUNTS)
(TEARS)
(RAGING)
(GRUNTING)
Brian! Brian!
(SCREAMS, GRUNTS)
JOE:
What are you doing?
Hey, come back! Brian!
(PANTING)
(CRYING)
Mum... (SOBBING)
...can you talk to God?
Can you say I'm real sorry?
Please, please,
let me come to you.
Please, Mama?
(CRYING SOFTLY)
-SISTER LUKE: Brian!
-JOE: Brian!
SISTER LUKE:
Brian?
JOE:
Brian!
SISTER AGNES:
Oh, dear. Brian!
Brian!
(PANTS)
Brian? Brian!
Who's Brian?
SISTER LUKE:
Brian!
JOE:
SISTER LUKE:
Brian!
(WOMAN HUMMING)
BISHOP:
It's time for
putting them out to pastures,
to Saint Stithian's
Retirement Home
for two of them,
and a frail-care facility
at Nazareth Place for the...
It seems to me that you haven't
acted on my instructions.
You were given
one small task.
We discussed it yesterday,
and for months before that.
-FATHER FINDLAY: Yes, but--
-BISHOP: The old ducks
have had a good run.
FATHER FINDLAY:
Couldn't we just--?
BISHOP:
It's time for change.
FATHER FINDLAY:
Couldn't we just, you know,
let nature take its course?
BISHOP:
The developer's offer
is on the table now.
Greaves is not a patient man.
FATHER FINDLAY:
Yeah, but tomorrow morning?
You heard me!
(THUDS)
(GASPING)
(GRUNTING)
Agnes? Agnes!
Brian! Are you all right?
Where have you been?
What did I tell you?
The boy should be at home
with his family,
not hanging about and making
a nuisance of himself.
He's having difficulties
at home.
Rugby! That's how you deal
with difficulties at home.
You know what they do
with people like you, boy?
They chuck you in jail.
-Prosecuted.
-That's enough.
Things are about
to change around here.
Place is falling apart.
It's a wreck.
And you!
You... can crochet my elbows.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
SISTER AGNES:
What's this?
Huh?
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Let's get you cleaned up.
Come on.
Find you something dry to wear
in the donations bin, hey?
"Retirement"?
-What?
-Father Findlay.
Oh, gone so soon!
(BOTH CHUCKLES)
Look.
Huh?
"Settled in a warm
and welcoming environment."
Ohh. Until they meet him.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, is that all there was?
Guess who's going to go
to a retirement place?
Tell them what you told me.
It's about the convent.
The bishop says
it's falling to pieces,
so a van's coming
tomorrow morning
to take you to...
a pasture?
Pasture?
Out... to pasture?
BRIAN:
What does that mean?
It means
they're sending us away, Brian.
Well...
(CHUCKLES)
I thought this was, uh...
about Findlay.
It's not. It's us.
BRIAN:
Not everyone.
The bishop said Sister Luke
can go to Nazareth.
-What?!
-Like the one in the Bible.
-Jesus liked it!
-Nazareth Place?
That's where
they tie people to the beds!
(♪♪♪)
Patricia.
50 years,
we've been caring
for this community.
50 years!
Fed the bellies.
Loved the babies.
Taught the children.
They can't just send us away.
Hello? Hello?
They've no right.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Have they not?
They most certainly do not.
We hold the lease
to the land. Us!
They can't just take it.
Go and find
the deeds to the convent.
Go and find them!
Hello! Patricia?
-Who's Patricia?
-She's not answering.
-(BANGS RECEIVER DOWN)
-She might be in court!
Patricia has them.
She took them away
for safekeeping
when she left.
Agnes, I can't find them!
Luke's right.
Patricia's got the deeds.
(DIALLING)
Patricia! Hello!
Patricia!
SISTER AGNES:
Oh, Luke, don't you--
(SNAPPING CABLE)
FATHER FINDLAY:
Agnes?
-Oh, Agnes. Ag--
-(SLAMS DOOR)
FATHER FINDLAY:
Oh, come now!
Look, we need a word.
Look. You knew
this day would come.
What's yours is ours.
I mean...
what's ours is ours.
Church is church.
They're coming
first thing in the morning.
Look, I'm sorry, all right?
I tried to talk them out of it.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
(BANGING DOOR)
(FATHER FINDLAY STUMBLES
AND GRUNTS)
Why would they--?
They can't send us away, Agnes.
We still serve!
It doesn't make sense.
(SISTER AGNES GASPS)
They've had
an offer on the land.
Well, that's who that was,
the baldy with the bishop--
a property man!
Patricia has the deeds.
Why don't
we just go get them?
SISTER AGNES:
Pack a bag.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
What? Have you lost your mind?
We can't just leave!
We can go,
or we can be removed.
Tomorrow morning they come,
Mary Clare!
Did you not hear?
SISTER MARY CLARE:
But the South Island?
BRIAN:
South Island?
SISTER MARY CLARE:
It's miles away!
BRIAN:
That's where Mum's from!
Patricia will sort it out.
BRIAN:
And I can come?
But, Agnes,
we can't move Sis--
No, you can't.
-What? Why not?
-Agnes!
-(BANGING DOOR)
BRIAN:
But Sister Agnes,
I have to come!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
We can't move Sister Luke!
She'll get confused!
BRIAN:
Sister Agnes?
Oh!
BRIAN:
Sister Agnes, please!
Why not?
It's not fair!
I've never seen snow!
(BANGING DOOR)
-BRIAN: Sister Agnes?
-SISTER MARY CLARE: Agnes!
The South Island?
That's Mum's island.
(SIGHS)
BRIAN:
I pray to them!
So I could go to her!
They're her mountains!
It's done, Sister!
It's happened! A miracle!
(SISTER AGNES COUGHS)
This is adult business, Brian.
Not some nice holiday
to visit friends.
I know!
And miracles are not gifts
given for being good
by some wizard in the sky.
Yes, but--
Hang a minute. What?
SISTER AGNES:
Get the fruitcake.
BRIAN:
Where?
-(LAUGHING)
-Luke! Where is the fruitcake?
BRIAN:
Found it!
SISTER AGNES:
Miracles happen when you
least expect them, Brian...
and not when you want it,
or the way you want it.
Only God knows,
and he shows us by--
by opening little doors.
You don't go through...
nothing happens.
Exactly! So I can come.
Where's Mary Clare? Mary Clare?
Get Sister Luke.
Mary Clare!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
I'm not coming!
What?
We cannot be here
when they come!
They'll drag us out!
Well, have you got
a better plan?
If we stay,
Luke goes to Nazareth,
and we never see her again!
(DOOR SHUTS)
(♪♪♪)
(CLOCK TICKING)
Is Father Findlay
gonna drive us?
Off a cliff, the state he's in.
-♪ Bring me my-- ♪
-Shh! Shh, shh, shh.
I've got two words for you,
and they're not
"happy birthday."
RACE ANNOUNCER: (ON TV)
And they're off!
Passing Wind flies by
on the outside.
Aw, what?
RACE ANNOUNCER: (ON TV)
Little Nickers
is kicking off nicely,
with Sotally Tober
close behind.
Sotally Tober drops back
as Golden Shower
rounds the bend!
They are neck and neck!
FATHER FINDLAY:
Aw, for pity's sake.
RACE ANNOUNCER: (ON TV)
Little Nickers,
everyone passes Passing Wind,
and who's that in the lead?
Sotally Tober!
Golden Shower loses steam...
-Yes!
-...and Sotally Tober wins!
Yes, you beauty!
RACE ANNOUNCER: (ON TV)
Sotally Tober is--
You beauty!
(♪♪♪)
(ENGINE STARTS, REVS)
BRIAN:
Sister Agnes,
can you even drive?
SISTER AGNES:
Decades of experience!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Not this decade.
Can you see any cars?
This is ridiculous, Agnes!
You're half blind!
Well, it's an old prescription.
I could... just borrow those.
Ah, that's better.
BRIAN: What?
Why are we going this way?
SISTER AGNES:
Because you're going home!
BRIAN:
But, Sister Agnes,
I'll be the most helpfullest.
♪ Mademoiselle
from Armentières ♪
♪ Parlez-vous ♪
♪ Mademoiselle
from Armentières ♪
Luke's pills!
We forgot her pills!
We have to go back.
-We can't.
-Agnes!
Mary Clare!
Sisters! I brung them.
Me. See?
I remember stuff.
My eyes is good.
"My eyes  are good."
No, they're not!
All your eyes is bad.
Watch out!
Oh!
(GRUNTS)
I can pick up
the little things,
'cause my fingers isn't stiff,
and I can hear,
not like you.
-I beg your pardon?
-Exactly!
-(GASPS)
-(BRAKES SCREECHING)
-(CATTLE LOWING)
-(HORN BLARING)
Hi-ya!
(GRUNTING)
(CATTLE LOWING)
SISTER AGNES:
Goodness.
Pukana!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
He'll have to come, Agnes.
JOE:
He doesn't deserve
a holiday, Agnes.
He ruined
Liz's wedding dress.
Well, it was my mum's dress.
It's not a holiday, Joseph.
It's a matter
of the utmost importance.
We're about to get thrown out.
Now, if we leave now,
we can get the last ferry,
and we stop
at St. Helen's down south,
then on to Patricia,
who's got the deeds.
-Patricia?
-Well, you remember Patricia.
She was a sister,
now she's a barrister.
Yeah, we all know
who Patricia is.
Paula's favourite auntie.
And Brian's great-auntie.
She left before
they had a chance to meet,
but now they can.
Up high, snow country.
Pack something warm.
Agnes. I didn't say he could!
He's got a way with the girls,
Joseph...
and you need a break.
SISTER LUKE:
♪ Parlez-vous... ♪
♪ Mademoiselle... ♪
(SISTER LUKE HUMMING)
Sister Mary Clare,
thank you very much.
-(KNOCKING WINDOW)
-Hey.
Now, listen to me, mate.
Just because I said
you could go doesn't mean
you don't owe someone
a jolly big apology.
And when you owe someone
an apology, you--
Shouldn't make them wait?
Right.
LIZ:
Here you go.
(WINDOW CRANKING)
Oi! What did I just say?
-Liz, thank you.
-Thank you.
(ENGINE STARTS)
♪ Mademoiselle
from Armentières ♪
♪ Parlez-vous ♪
♪ Mademoiselle
from Armentières ♪
Oh, Joe!
We didn't give them any money.
-(BANGS)
-JOE: Cheese and rice!
I guess
they'll be home soon, then.
Ugh.
(♪♪♪)
♪  Well, now, some people dig
Matthew, Mark, Luke, or John ♪
♪  Them four boys could preach
it, son, don't get me wrong ♪
♪ When I need something
make me sing and shout ♪
♪  I throw my hands up
and drive the Devil out ♪
♪ Make me moan, make me cry,
Stand up and testify ♪
♪ Send for Sister,
Mavis, mm-hmm ♪
♪ Send for Sister Mavis,
mm-hmm ♪
♪ Mahalia and Rosetta,
No, you won't find a better ♪
♪ Holy Trinity to save us ♪
♪ Send for Sister,
Mavis, mm-hmm ♪
♪ Send for Sister Mavis,
mm-hmm ♪
♪ She get the holy roller,
set the soul on fire ♪
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Got a ticket, have you, Agnes?
It's summer holidays.
We'll never get on.
SISTER AGNES:
I'll try for the night ferry.
(ENTRANCE BELL RINGS)
Excuse me.
Kia ora.
Oh! Bless you, my child.
AGENT:
I'm sorry, sir.
The ferry's full.
You should've
made a reservation.
Now, Madam--
We need to get a car
on the ferry.
Oh... is this
what I think it is?
Homemade, matured,
spirit-bathed.
Are we still talking
about the fruitcake?
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(STAMPING)
Enjoy the trip, Madam.
Thank you.
I'm sorry,
the ferry's full.
(FERRY HORN BELLOWING)
We're-- we're going
over the sea!
Come up with me.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
No.
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
Good morning.
Hmm.
Oh, Mary Clare.
For goodness sake.
(SIGHS)
We had to go.
No, we didn't.
Leaving was a terrible idea.
We could have stayed to fight.
Fight.
Don't be ridiculous.
They just would've taken Luke.
Oh...
Where is Luke?
SISTER AGNES AND MARY CLARE:
Luke!
BRIAN:
Sister!
Luke? Brian!
BRIAN:
Aue! That's yucky!
FISHERMAN:
Put 'em in the bucket, boy.
Ugh!
Fillet it like this, boy.
Eyes on the blade.
Never forget that.
BRIAN:
Aah!
Feel the fish guts!
It's squishy.
-SISTER AGNES: Brian!
-Hi, Sister Agnes.
Luke!
Nae guts, nae glory!
No, don't, Sister, aw...
BRIAN:
(INDISTINCT SPEECH)
(LAUGHING)
BRIAN:
Aw...
you're so stinky, Sister Luke!
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Where's my car?
Where's my car?!
Oh, the ticket!
Oh, no, the ticket!
Ah-ha!
No, the ticket!
Ah, God.
(LYRICS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(♪♪♪)
Hey, they were-- they were
picked up this morning?
-Yes.
-The retirement home?
What did you say to them?
Um, I did
exactly as instructed.
No fuss?
Good. Well, very good.
You did--
you did good, Findlay.
Yeah, I remember.
Should be plain sailing, then.
Not messy like down south.
(WHISTLES)
All right,
let's get things moving!
(TRUCK ENGINE REVS)
Come on, hustle.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Goodness me, you smell.
SISTER LUKE:
Time for a piddle!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Oh, piddle you shall.
BRIAN:
How much longer,
Sister Mary Clare?
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Oh, it's just moments away.
SISTER AGNES:
We'll overnight
with our sisters at St. Helen's.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Then on to Patricia's
in the morning.
SISTER LUKE:
St. Helen's
and my dear Sister Hildegard.
Sister Hildegard makes
the best kumara stew
that I bet you're just about
ready for, Brian.
With red rascal potatoes
from my garden.
BRIAN:
Red rascal? (LAUGHS)
SISTER AGNES:
The garden is a veritable Eden.
SISTER LUKE:
We swap seeds
from Singapore to Sweden.
BRIAN:
Garden of Sweden!
When you make an omelette,
use a fork,
not an egg beater.
Don't forget!
How could I?
You tell me every day.
-I do not.
-BRIAN: You do, though!
SISTER AGNES:
Our sisters will
be delighted and delightful.
Praise God.
I'm just about ready
to put my feet up.
(PULLS HANDBRAKE)
(SHUTS CAR DOOR)
Sister Hildegard!
Where is she?
Ag... Agnes.
Where is our Sister Hildegard?
(♪♪♪)
Where are we?
Agnes? Agnes, where--?
Shh, shh, shh.
Luke, it's all right.
It's all right.
W-- what has happened?
SISTER LUKE:
Where are we?
(CRYING)
My garden.
My garden!
-(CRYING)
-Shh, shh, shh.
Agnes...
Ag... I want to go home.
(CRIES)
(CAR APPROACHING)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Why in good God's name
were we not told?
We could have taken them in.
Where are they, Agnes?
Uh... where are we?
All those years
we lived there together...
and no one
thought to tell us.
We trusted them.
Why didn't they trust us enough
to bring us in
on their decision?
Why trust a lying,
thieving developer
instead of their own sisters?
They betrayed us, Agnes.
I vowed I would never
let anyone betray me again.
Stop the car!
I want to get out.
Listen to me!
Stop the car!
-All right, right. Ugh.
-SISTER MARY CLARE: Agnes!
SISTER AGNES:
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
-I said stop the car!
-All right, all right.
-Are you deaf? You hearing me?
-Calm yourself!
-Oh--
-I mean it!
SISTER AGNES: Good grief.
-I want to get out!
-I know that. I know that.
I'm just trying to find
a place to pull over.
-Let me out!
-I don't know where I am.
-I want to get out!
-I know!
Oh, goodness,
I think I'm on the beach.
Oh, Mary Clare!
BRIAN:
Sister! What--?
(PULLS HANDBRAKE)
SISTER AGNES:
Mary Clare!
Brian, what-- ugh.
Oh. Come on, Luke.
-SISTER LUKE: No!
-SISTER AGNES: Luke!
SISTER LUKE:
I'm not going out there.
BRIAN:
Sister, come back!
SISTER AGNES:
Luke, come out.
-No. Don't--
-What're you doing?
Surely you need a piddle.
SISTER LUKE:
I'm not--
I'm not gonna--
I'm not going in there!
SISTER AGNES:
No one's asking you to go in!
That's not why we're here.
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry, dear.
I didn't mean to shout.
(CRYING QUIETLY)
BRIAN:
God will protect you, Sister.
That's what you
and Sister Agnes tell me.
Trusting and all that.
And it's true.
That's what we teach...
in our small town,
in our small world...
But out here...
reminds me of things
I don't want to think about.
What things?
The ocean.
The sea.
Crossing the sea
when I was a little girl.
"I'll come for you,"
she said.
"When things get better,
I'll come..."
But she never did.
BRIAN:
Your mum?
Yeah.
Why?
(SNIFFLES)
They put me on a boat,
and they said
they'd tell her where I was,
but they never did.
Your mum?
Yeah, my mum.
Did you write her a letter?
Lots of letters, but...
(SIGHS)
I didn't know
where to send them.
(chuckling sadly)
Sometimes people steal children
from their families,
saying it's good for them,
but it's cruel.
It's so cruel.
But you...
you, Brian...
you've got a family...
a family
that's waiting for you...
a family that loves you.
(SIGHS, SNIFFLES)
(SOBS, SNIFFLES)
Look, I--
I know it's hard,
and I know you're scared,
Mary Clare,
but we're going to fix this,
and-- and I...
Oh, dear.
BRIAN:
Sister Luke,
you are very holey!
Thanks. I try!
(GRUNTS)
SISTER AGNES:
Luke! Where are you going?
-Luke! Oh, no!
-Stop!
SISTER AGNES:
Mary Clare, stop her!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Come back, Luke! Come back!
SISTER AGNES:
Oh, my God.
-SISTER MARY CLARE: Oh no!
-SISTER AGNES: Oh, she's under!
She's going to drown. Luke!
-(GRUNTING)
-(SISTER LUKE LAUGHS)
SISTER AGNES:
Heavy.
(LAUGHING)
BRIAN:
Turn around,
you silly sausage!
SISTER AGNES:
Look at you,
you're soaked.
-(GIGGLING)
-I'm soaked!
♪ Haere mai ♪
♪ Everything is kapai ♪
♪ You're here at last ♪
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Avert your eyes!
BRIAN:
Averting my eyes.
Averting my eyes!
♪ Haere mai ♪
♪ Not a cloud in the sky ♪
SISTER AGNES:
God is great.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
And greatly to be praised.
♪ To coin a phrase ♪
♪ This is the day of days ♪
(CHUCKLING)
♪ You're welcome
as the sunshine ♪
♪ You're welcome as a king ♪
(HORN BLARES)
♪ Pai kare, this is one time ♪
♪ We'll really have a fling ♪
♪ Haere mai ♪
♪ Everything is kapai ♪
♪ Throughout the land ♪
♪ We want to shake your hand ♪
♪ Haere mai ♪
♪ We're proud of you
that's why ♪
(♪♪♪)
♪ Haere mai ♪
♪ Everything is kapai ♪
♪ You're here at last ♪
♪ You're really here at-- ♪
(RADIO STATIC)
SISTER LUKE:
I'm starving.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Where are we
gonna stay tonight, Agnes?
We've got no food, no money,
and soon we'll have no petrol.
(ANGELIC CHOIR SINGS)
SISTER AGNES:
What are these?
BRIAN:
Sister Agnes!
They are pears.
Well, I know that,
but where'd you find them?
St. Helen's, while youse
was all wailing and whining.
(MUNCHES)
Oh... they taste like home!
-Sticky.
-Mm. Juicy!
See if there's any hankies
in the glove compartment.
(PAPERS RUSTLING)
No, just race tickets.
What's-- what's that,
in there?
"Done Be-gin."
"Gol-den sh..."
They're always silly names.
"Done Beggin'.
Golden Shower.
Sotally Tober."
Uhh. Totally sober.
Sotally Tober.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
Let me see that.
RACE ANNOUNCER:
Golden Shower loses steam,
and Sotally Tober wins!
Oh, dear.
Father Findlay'll
be missing this.
(CHUCKLING)
(♪♪♪)
You want it, you do it.
I can't be seen in there.
I'm the Mother Superior.
"I shall not fall
into temptation."
Luke 40:22.
Temptation?
"All gifts come from above."
James 1:17.
"Genitals like donkeys."
Ezekiel 23:20.
Ugh.
Brian... where do you think--
what do you think you're doing?
What I do for Dad.
It's not rocket surgery.
No, no! Don't!
Wait!
Don't tell them we sent you.
Tell them...
Tell them--
Dad is in the pub.
Mum needs bread.
Oh, God.
You think
they'll believe him?
(SIGHS)
Ah! Bless you,
Father Findlay...
...for your filthy habits.
(TSKING)
(STRIKES MATCH)
Ahh...
Oh!
No...
(COUGHING)
Oh!
Uh!
SISTER AGNES:
The first thing
we're buying is denture cream.
Oh.
SISTER AGNES:
He's back.
They gave me this.
(COINS RATTLING)
-Oh!
Oh, thank you.
They said
we could keep the bag.
Aah!
Agnes, drive!
(GASPING)
Woo!
(ENGINE STARTS, REVS)
(TYRES SQUEALING)
SISTER AGNES:
Lord, thank you
for the bountiful gifts
you have bestowed
on your loyal servants.
Thank you for the gift of--
You should see this place, Mum!
Real fancy.
Toilet's not even
in the bathroom.
Oh, and Sister Agnes says
it's only right
we get the ticket money
because church is church,
just like Father Findlay said,
and they done all his mending.
(WHISPERS)
I think it might've
been a miracle, Mum,
'cause the glove compartment,
it was like a little door...
and it opened!
Sister Agnes says
we'll be there tomorrow.
Tomorrow, Mum.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Agnes, a phone!
Call Patricia!
It... (SIGHS)
It just beeps.
Why does it beep?
Oh, it's broken!
No, Luke!
What?
(clicking)
I suppose you brought
Patricia's number?
Uh, yes, I memorized it.
I-is it 635 or 645?
(WHISPERING)
She's forgotten it.
Oh. Doesn't matter.
(♪♪♪)
(UNDOING CLASPS)
You all right, Brian Collins?
Mm-hmm.
(SIGHS)
They'd be gone now,
wouldn't they, Agnes?
Yes, Mary Clare.
(CHUCKLING)
What I wouldn't give
to have seen their faces.
Knocking at our front door...
(ALL CHUCKLE)
...you know,
waiting to push us around.
Woo-woo! Nobody home!
(CHUCKLING)
Driving away
in an empty van.
(LAUGHING)
Ah, we did it, girls.
We beat 'em.
Hope so, Agnes.
In God we trust!
And seeds, and beans.
(BREAKING WIND)
(LAUGHING)
BRIAN:
Oi, Sister Luke!
(CLOCK TICKING)
Now, the staircase
might be worth something,
but the rest...
nah.
So, this is part of it?
No, no, that's the presbytery.
That's mine.
Oh, that's yours, is it?
No. We need this
for the onramp.
With a petrol station
and motel going in,
we need
to maximize the footprint.
You know, my man
over at land disposals
will fast-track
the whole consent.
I'll get the locksmith over.
Well, no,
you can't just break in.
Your Excellency,
this has gone too far.
WOMAN:
Father Bishop?
Where are the sisters?
48 hours,
then we can start.
You know, you'll want
the fuel tank sunk here.
Parking this side.
The onramp, yeah,
just over there.
(♪♪♪)
Father Findlay?
Christchurch?
That's the most holiest town
I've ever heard of.
SISTER AGNES:
City, not town.
It has a cathedral.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
A city we'll never arrive at,
the way you're driving.
(CLICKS)
RADIO ANNOUNCER: (ON RADIO)
Weather, it looks like
it's five seasons
in one day today.
For anyone in the Twizel area,
you're in for a cold snap.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
DJ: (ON RADIO)
Thanks for that, Darla.
Over to the news.
We've got a collision
between a sheep truck
and a tractor,
so if you're, uh,
travelling that way,
plenty of free manure
on the road.
♪ Good tidings we bring ♪
BRIAN:
Snow?
SISTER LUKE:
Time for a piddle!
BRIAN:
Oh. Hail.
Time for a piddle.
SISTER AGNES:
Not now, Sister Luke!
SISTER LUKE:
Time for a piddle!
SISTER AGNES:
Sister Luke, are you sure?
SISTER LUKE:
Piddle! Piddle!
(RAIN PATTERNS, THUNDER RUMBLES)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Sister Luke!
Quickly, dear.
No, I'm not coming!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Oh...
SISTER LUKE:
No! Not coming.
No, thank you.
-Sister Luke!
-The Von Trapp family--
-Sister Luke--
SISTER LUKE:
No!
-(GLASS SHATTERS)
-(GASPING)
(DOOR SHUTS)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Thanks.
Oh...
SISTER AGNES:
Oh dear.
Oh...
Ah, there it is.
Aoraki.
The cloud piercer.
The sacred place.
(♪♪♪)
You're sopping wet!
Oh...
I just remembered!
Have one of Liz's biscuits.
Here.
Oh, thank you.
Me too, please.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Oh, God bless our Liz.
-Brian?
-Mm!
Yuck.
Uh, Brian, now, come.
Elizabeth Fletcher
is not the abomination
you think she is.
She is a bombed nation.
She hates me.
"Hate" is a very strong word,
Brian Collins.
Doesn't sit well
with Himself.
(HORN HONKING)
(ANGELIC CHOIR SINGS)
I am driving
as fast as is humanly possible
in unsafe conditions!
(MULTIPLE HORNS HONKING)
BRIAN:
They want you
to go faster, Sister.
(HORNS HONKING)
I can't.
BRIAN:
"Can't" is a very strong word.
(HORNS HONKING CONTINUES)
I won't.
(MULTIPLE HORNS HONKING)
(♪♪♪)
(HONKING)
♪ Vente ♪
♪ Episcopalis hominem ♪
(SHEEP BLEATING)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
You know what, Luke?
You still smell.
SISTER LUKE:
Yes, probably.
PATRICIA:
Oh, my goodness!
Luke! Oh, my darlings!
Is it really you?
What are you doing here?
SISTER AGNES:
Well, I'm sorry
we're here unannounced...
PATRICIA:
Sorry?
You came to see your sis!
SISTER LUKE:
'Cause we missed
you! Couldn't resist you!
Oh, my darlings!
Mwah!
Oh... who have we got here?
Brian.
Paula's boy.
PATRICIA:
My Paula?
I'm your Auntie Patricia.
Auntie Patricia
of the plum duff pudding?
The very same--
plum duff, pudding, and cream,
if you're anything
like your mum.
I am very like my mum.
You certainly are.
Thank you for bringing me
my Moko.
Come on, darling!
You must be bored stiff.
(LAUGHS)
(KNOCKS DOOR)
(DOOR OPENS)
-Father Findlay.
-About the boy?
I need a word.
Pardon?
Brian.
Where is he?
Where are the sisters?
-Let me speak to Joe.
-I'll let you speak to me.
They're gone.
Gone? What do you mean? Where?
What do you care?
After everything
they did for you,
for the community,
you turned your back on them.
Are they coming back?
Despite what
they may have told you,
it would be within
their best interests to return.
Ahh.
Their best interests.
It's not just the retirement.
It's Harry Greaves.
He's not just taking the home,
he's tearing it down.
I need to wash her habit.
Oh, yes. Just down the hall.
Help yourselves, darling.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, Agnes...
you drove all this way.
What's going on?
Oh, sit down.
Patricia,
they're sending us away.
To a pasture.
A home, Patricia.
Bishop Chaytor's moving fast.
A property developer
sniffed us out.
What? When did they
tell you that?
The day before yesterday.
Oh, you can't be serious!
Oh, gosh.
(SIGHS)
(SOBBING)
Sister Luke...
they want to put her
in Nazareth.
BRIAN:
Not the one in the Bible.
Nazareth Place?
Those bastards!
What about Findlay?
Oh, you know him.
(SNIFFLES)
Should have said something,
didn't...
too busy with his liquor
and his horses.
Chaytor is leading the charge
with a property man,
of all people.
I-- I...
you know, I just thought
it'd be different
when our time came,
and we'd still be together.
PATRICIA:
Now, listen.
Leave this to me.
Patricia...
do you have the deeds?
-Of course.
-Ahh!
Luke was right. Dear Luke.
And they can't just
take it away, can they?
No, no. The nuns hold
a whenua lease over Maori land.
Remember?
We talked about that
before I left.
I'll go through
and check the files.
Whose car is that?
It's Father Findlay's.
I stole it.
Stole!
You did a sin.
You should be prostituted.
Oh... it's a little
late for that.
-(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
-(HAMMERING)
(♪♪♪)
And I suppose
you get to keep your presbytery.
Well... look.
We've got to get them back.
JOE:
They're at Sister Patricia's.
We've got to let them know.
Well, I don't have a number,
and they said
they'll be back in a few days.
It's a few days too late.
This is your fault,
Father Findlay.
You fix it.
(HAMMERING)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(♪♪♪)
BRIAN:
Sister Agnes--
SISTER AGNES:
Shush, Brian!
Patricia is concentrating.
Brian, come here.
You know what nuns do
when they're not praying
or mending
or driving
really, really slowly?
Look at this.
Now, press that.
(CLICKS BUTTON)
How about that?
♪ Are you sure your prayers
haven't been answered? ♪
♪ Now, think ♪
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Come on, Agnes!
You remember this one!
♪ ...sure your prayers
haven't been answered? ♪
♪ Now, think ♪
♪ Brother, think ♪
♪ Don't you dare think
the good lord-- ♪
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Come on!
You love this one!
♪ Everything you do ♪
♪ Stop right now and take ♪
♪ Inventory ♪
♪ You'll come up with
a different story ♪
♪ 'Cause he sees
every move you make ♪
♪ Every waggle of your head ♪
♪ Every wink of an eye ♪
♪ It's his laugh
you're laughing ♪
♪ And his tears you cry ♪
♪ You may not know how to pray ♪
♪ But he loves you
when you try ♪
♪ So raise your voices high ♪
♪ And the Lord will hear you ♪
♪ Hear you, ohh ♪
♪ He sees every move you make ♪
♪ Every waggle of your head ♪
♪ Every wink of an eye ♪
♪ It's his laugh
you're laughing ♪
♪ His tears you cry ♪
♪ You may not know
how to pray ♪
♪ But he loves you
when you try ♪
♪ So raise your voices high ♪
♪ And the Lord will hear you,
hear you ♪
♪ Are you sure, real sure ♪
♪ They haven't been answered? ♪
♪ Now, think ♪
♪ Oh, brother, think ♪
♪ Don't you dare think
the good Lord ♪
♪ Didn't stop to hear you ♪
♪ He hears and sees
everything you do ♪
♪ Stop right now
and take inventory ♪
♪ You'll come up
with a different story ♪
♪ 'Cause he sees
every move you make ♪
♪ Every waggle of your head ♪
♪ Every wink of your eye ♪
(EXHALES)
♪ It's his laugh
you're laughing ♪
♪ His tears you cry ♪
♪ You may not know
how to pray ♪
♪ But he loves you
when you try ♪
♪ So raise your voices high ♪
♪ And the Lord will hear you ♪
(PAPER TEARS)
Ohh!
(♪♪♪)
PATRICIA:
Uh, you took over
Sister Suzanne's...
when, Agnes? '37?
And the lease deeds
were lodged with the district?
-Yes.
-And it all closed in '64?
That sounds about right.
Oh, Brian, look!
Your mum and dad.
BRIAN:
I can't really see her.
I can never see her.
PATRICIA:
Come with me, moko.
Of all my special things...
I saved this one for you.
They were
going to bury this with her,
but I asked to take it...
Your mum's.
BRIAN:
And we'll go,
Sister Agnes?
Where?
BRIAN:
To the mountain.
Mum's mountain.
SISTER AGNES:
Well, now, I told you, Brian,
it's not a holiday.
Well, let's talk about it
in the morning.
It's, uh... it's...
it's time for your bed now.
It's very late.
PATRICIA:
Wrap up tight.
Tawhiri's breath
will be makariri tonight.
Oh, Agnes, we should take him.
We've come this far.
(SIGHS)
I love you.
(CHUCKLING)
I love you too, Luke.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm glad we came, Agnes.
Thank you.
Mary Clare... thank you.
(♪♪♪)
Thank you, Liz.
(GASPS)
(♪♪♪)
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
FATHER FINDLAY: (ON PHONE)
Patricia?
It's Father Findlay.
Hang on.
Father Findlay.
PATRICIA: (ON PHONE)
What do you want?
It's rather late.
Well, I'm sorry about that,
but I need to speak
to the sisters.
I know they're there.
PATRICIA: (ON PHONE)
The sisters are sleeping
after a long
and harrowing journey.
I will be acting
as legal counsel
in all matters
pertaining to their retirement.
Well, I just thought
you might like to know...
a little while ago, I s--
I was made to sign
an-an addendum.
What addendum?
FATHER FINDLAY: (ON PHONE)
It wasn't me.
It was, you know,
the authorities-- superiors.
Anyway, you'll find it
in the files,
the back page.
Check the fine print.
Well, I realize now
that it may not have been
the right thing to do,
and I'm sorry.
Father Findlay...
I do not have the time
or the crayons
to explain to you
how much you have messed up
on this,
but I will be sending
the paperwork
to dissolve the addendum,
and you will sign it.
-Well--
-Wait!
You will,
if you want a place
to live out your days.
If they go, you go. Get it?
(WIND HOWLING)
Agnes!
Come, come and sit down.
Please. I've got news.
Harry Greaves claims
that you no longer
occupy the property,
that you've abandoned it,
at which point
it reverts to the church,
and they'll control it.
You inadvertently
played into his hands.
I'm-- I'm not quite--
Leaving was the worst thing
you could have done.
Everything,
and I mean everything--
-In a miniskirt!
-(BOTH LAUGHING)
... hinges on
you being there in residence.
We shouldn't have left?
You can save the convent,
but you have to be there.
(CHUCKLES)
I left it in the dryer!
SISTER AGNES:
How long
before the wrecking ball?
The what?!
How long?
PATRICIA:
Tomorrow.
Midday the demolition starts,
but you can stop them
if you leave now.
(THUDDING)
Take this,
and get back by noon.
Where is my garden?
Where is my Brian?
Where is Brian?
-Oh, goodness.
-(BLARING HORN)
PATRICIA:
Brian? Brian!
Kia there, moko! Hurry up.
Brian?
Brian!
PATRICIA:
Moko? Come on!
Brian?
Brian!
(♪♪♪)
I'm here, Mum.
Mum?
WOMAN:
Brian.
BRIAN:
♪ Haere Mai ♪
♪ Everything is kapai ♪
(♪♪♪)
Come on, moko.
Come on, Brian.
(WIND WHISTLING)
ALL:
Brian!
-Brian!
Brian's glove!
Oh.
(WIND WHISTLING)
Haere mai. I'm here, Mum!
Here I am.
Here-- Here, Mum!
(DISTANT VOICES)
Brian!
(SHIVERING)
SISTER AGNES:
Brian!
-Brian!
He must be close now.
Luke?
(WIND WHISTLING)
Sister Luke!
Luke!
(WIND WHISTLING)
(♪♪♪)
♪ Haere Mai ♪
♪ Everything is kapai ♪
♪ Kua tae mai koe ♪
♪ Ki te tautoko e ♪
Brian Te Wera Collins.
Where was you, Mum?
Why did you take so long?
I was forgetting
what you looked like...
what you sound like.
-Ohh...
-I thought you was gone.
No.
There's no such thing
as gone, Brian.
No such thing.
(CRYING)
But I want to come now.
I want to come now!
SISTER AGNES:
Luke!
(WIND WHOOSHING)
Brian!
Luke!
Brian...
Mum?
I owe someone
a very big apology.
And when you owe someone
an apology...
TOGETHER:
You shouldn't
make them wait.
(♪♪♪)
SISTER LUKE: (DISTANT VOICE)
Hoo hoo!
SISTER AGNES:
Luke!
Hoo hoo!
ALL:
Luke!
Hoo hoo!
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Luke! Oh! Luke!
Oh, no!
SISTER LUKE:
Hoo hoo!
Brian?
(GASPING)
Wake up, darling.
Come back to us.
Oh!
Please wake up, Brian.
Come... come back to us.
-Wake up.
-Come back.
I've failed you, little one.
My moko.
Oh. Oh, yes.
I'm sorry, Brian.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Sweet little boy.
-Oh...
-Mum.
Mum was there.
She said my name.
She said I had...
something to do.
Agnes, girls...
I've gotta go home!
(♪♪♪)
PATRICIA:
Come back to us soon, Brian.
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
You tell your sisters
Auntie loves them.
We love you too.
Thank you!
SISTER AGNES:
Is everyone
here and accounted for?
Brian?
I'm here!
Sister Luke?
Whoo-hoo!
You'll need cash.
Here we are.
Oh, no.
We've got lots of that.
-Oh!
-What the hell?
(SISTER MARY CLARE CHUCKLES)
-Okay, bye!
-Bye!
(engine revs)
Love you!
(♪♪♪)
She said my name.
And mine.
What is your name?
Brian!
(BOTH CRACKLING)
(♪♪♪)
♪ Queenie, Queenie,
don't drop the ball ♪
♪ Down come baby,
cradle and all ♪
♪ Queenie, Queenie,
don't drop the ball ♪
(CAR WHOOSHES)
BRIAN:
Faster, Sister Agnes!
We're never gonna make it,
not at this rate.
SISTER LUKE:
Rattle your dags, girl!
BRIAN:
Faster!
Come on, faster!
Come on, Agnes.
You can do it!
-Yes!
-Woo-hoo!
♪ Queenie, Queenie,
don't drop the ball ♪
Come on, come on.
-Yeah!
-Woo-hoo!
-Yay!
SISTER LUKE:
Go, go!
(CHUCKLES GIDDILY)
SISTER LUKE:
Keep the heat!
BRIAN:
Off we go!
See?
♪ What's a stay-at-home
Mama do with all that time? ♪
BRIAN:
Yeah! Whoo-hoo!
♪ Queenie, Queenie,
don't drop the ball ♪
♪ Down come baby,
cradle and all ♪
(LAUGHING)
Look at their little faces!
MAN:
(INDISTINCT SPEECH)
(BLOWS A KISS)
(GASPING)
SISTER AGNES:
Holy Mary, Most Immaculate,
to you I entrust
their sickly souls.
(SIGHS)
(PULLS HANDBRAKE)
I'm sorry, Mary Clare.
I'm sorry about everything.
(SIGHS)
I know.
It's all right.
(CAR DOOR OPENS, SHUTS)
Shift over.
Come on, dear. Move.
All right.
Sister Mary Clare can drive?
Agnes had the Morry,
but I...
(revving)
...had the tractor!
(SCREECHES)
Oh... oh! Oh!
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
(ENGINE ROARING)
(GASPS)
Oh...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN:
Hey! Whoo-hoo!
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT SPEECH)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
(REVS, WHIRS)
Oh, she wants to race!
She wants to race!
SISTER AGNES:
They're not
letting us overtake.
Slow down, ya idiot!
(TRUCK HORN HONKING)
Sister!
(HONKING)
SISTER AGNES: Mary Clare...
Mary Clare!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
SISTER AGNES:
Holy goodness me!
(WHOOSHES)
Amateurs!
(HORN HONKING)
BRIAN:
She can drive!
Not a word of this
to your father, Brian.
Oh...
(CHUCKLING)
Time for a piddle.
No!
(♪♪♪)
BRIAN:
Take this way.
It's shorter, Sister.
Oh, come on!
(BLEATING)
-SISTER LUKE: Move it!
-There's nobody in town!
-(HORN HONKING)
-(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Move! Move!
-SISTER LUKE:Get out of the way!
-BRIAN: Shoo! Shoo!
They're so stupid!
BRIAN:
Move! Go!
Go!
(HORN HONKING)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
The ferry's
gonna leave without us.
(HORN HONKING)
(DOG BARKING)
SISTER LUKE:
Show us the way, doggie!
(dog barking)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
We're not
gonna make the ferry!
SISTER AGNES:
How's the petrol?
I mean, how much time
have we lost?
SISTER MARY CLARE:
We're late!
SISTER LUKE:
Piddle...
SISTER AGNES:
Oh, dear Lord.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
How far
to the next town, Brian?
SISTER LUKE:
Brian, check the map.
BRIAN:
Um... not too far.
Oh!
-Too far.
-Oh no!
We believe in miracles,
don't we, Brian?
We sure do, Sister.
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
(GRUNTS)
SISTER LUKE:
Come on!
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(♪♪♪)
(ANGELIC CHOIR SINGS)
-Luke!
-Luke, what are you doing?
-Where are you going?
-SISTER LUKE: Hang on a sec!
Luke! Luke?
(LAUGHS)
SISTER AGNES:
Luke, hurry up, girl! Get in.
-(ENGINE REVS)
-(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Keep the change!
Jesus Christ!
Blasphemery!
(ALL CHEERING)
(SIREN WAILING)
SISTER AGNES:
Oh, come on!
Don't worry. I've got this.
(STRIKES MATCH)
(TAKING DRAGS)
(GRAVEL CRUNCHING)
I have two words to say to you.
Merry Christmas.
We have a ferry to catch?
Main unit?
I've got a 10-29-52-42
Blue Peter
up there on State Highway 63.
I'm going to need
a special clearance.
HELEN: (ON RADIO)
Oh, speak English, Kevin!
Uh, sorry, Helen.
Can you just give Jeff
a call at the ferry?
Ask him nicely to wait?
HELEN: (ON RADIO)
Oh, right-o!
Great, and, uh,
put the kettle on.
I'll be back soon.
Uh, roger. 10-4!
God bless you, my child!
(PANTING)
Follow the cop.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(♪♪♪)
-Pure violet!
-Woo-hoo!
Five hours till cut-off,
Mary Clare!
You can do it!
(ENGINE REVS)
BRIAN:
What if we don't make it?
Shh!
(WHOOSHES)
(LOWING)
SISTER AGNES:
You drove
the church tractor like this?
SISTER MARY CLARE:
By moonlight! Nothing like it.
SISTER LUKE:
♪ Hasn't been kissed
for 40 years ♪
♪ Hinky-dinky parlez-vous ♪
(ANGELIC CHOIR SINGS)
SISTER LUKE:
♪ Parlez-vous ♪
♪ Mademoiselle
from Armentières ♪
-BRIAN: Watch out!
-(TIRES SQUEAL)
♪ Mademoiselle
from Armentières ♪
♪ Parlez-vous ♪
Have a prune.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Me too, please.
BRIAN:
Faster.
Whoa!
SISTER AGNES:
She's overheating!
Come on, darling.
You can do it!
SISTER AGNES:
Don't slow down!
Five minutes, Mary Clare.
Five minutes and it's all over.
-Not on my watch!
-Stop!
No, we can't.
You have to!
Stop, stop, stop!
Brian, no!
I need out here!
Stop at my house.
I'm getting out!
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(DOOR OPENS)
-Brian!
-BRIAN: Go, go, go!
-Are you ready, dear?
-(ENGINE REVVING)
Drive it, girl...
like a tractor!
(GRAVEL SPITTING)
Brian.
Welcome back.
I got your note.
(PAPER RUSTLES)
And you're right...
I'm not your mother.
I'm real, real sorry.
(SIGHS)
We only have one mum, Brian...
...and I can never
be that for you.
What, then?
Your friend?
Maybe just... Liz.
Yeah.
Okay.
Where is everyone?
Oh, Brian,
they're at the convent.
-They're tearing--
-No! Come on!
-Oh!
-We got to get there!
(TYRES SQUEALING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(♪♪♪)
(CLOCK TICKING)
FATHER FINDLAY:
Where are they?
Come on, my darlings.
(ENGINE REVS)
Is that them?
(TYRES SQUEALING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
GREAVES:
No!
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHS)
SISTER AGNES:
Mary Clare!
(♪♪♪)
(ENGINE KNOCKING AND STALLING)
(EXHALING TENSELY)
(SIGHS)
(CLOCK STRIKING)
(CHEERING)
WOMAN FROM CROWD:
Hey!
FATHER FINDLAY:
Yes!
-Run, sisters!
-Run!
Faster, sisters!
Come on, girls!
Joe! Hitch him!
Oh, God! Findlay, grab him!
(GRUNTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
MAN FROM CROWD:
Faster, sisters!
Yes, sisters!
Your Excellency,
the nuns are not ready
for retirement,
and this home remains ours
as long as we are here.
GREAVES:
Yeah, but you
weren't here, were you?
You abandoned the property!
Sisters,
if you planned to return,
you'd have told someone.
We were always
coming back, Bishop.
Why didn't you ask us?
We'd have told you.
We took a short trip.
A slight vacation.
-A holiday!
(CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
Nuns don't take holy days.
But we did, Bishop...
and we came home.
SISTER AGNES:
By the laws
of your own diocese,
we, the nuns
of Sister Suzanne's,
shall remain here so long
as we are in service...
(STRAINING)
(SPITS)
(UNLOCKING)
(DOOR BANGS OPEN, CREAKS)
(TOGETHER):
...and in residence!
Yeah, sisters!
(CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
You'll be hearing
from me, Sister.
Well, I look forward
to that, Your Grace.
(CHEERING AND LAUGHING)
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Oh, Father...
she corners
like she's on rails.
Might need a touch of water.
Ha. Not to worry, not to worry.
Um, Sister Agnes, um,
on your travels,
did you happen to find...
um...
-A race ticket?
-Yes.
We cashed it.
And on behalf of your parish,
we'd like to thank you
for your generosity, Father,
and I don't know
if you've noticed,
but this convent needs
a little bit of a, you know...
freshening-up.
I've had some thoughts...
which I think
you will find quite agreeable...
since they involve
you having somewhere to live.
Oh, darling! Hello.
Sweet, sweet hello.
(SIGHS)
I was worried about you.
I saw snow.
You did?
I saw Mum.
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry, Dad.
I missed you, my boy.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Luke!
Oh, there you are!
(SISTER MARY CLARE LAUGHS)
You missed the shenanigans.
You should've seen
Father Findlay's face.
You asleep?
Luke...
Oh, no.
Oh, no, Luke!
Oh, my darling.
Oh, Luke.
(CRIES) Oh...
Oh, Luke!
(WEEPING)
Oh, Lord...
we entrust our sister to you.
May she rest in peace
in your hands...
and...
thank you for bringing her
back to her beloved garden.
May she bring the same joy
to your heavenly Eden.
Oh, Luke...
(SOBS, SNIFFLES)
Oh.
Mum said her name...
...so she went.
SISTER MARY CLARE:
Oh...
Agnes, our sister's gone home.
What a way to go.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(SIGHS)
(♪♪♪)
SISTER AGNES:
Ah, you've repaired it.
The magic returns.
I've been meaning
to get back to you
about miracles, Brian.
I was wrong, you see.
They're not little doors?
No, they're not
just little doors.
They're big ones too.
How big?
Well...
they're big enough
to pull you through,
right through,
into another place.
The top of a mountain?
Indeed.
Or right into the...
the grand mystery itself.
And I see now that, uh,
that death
is a miracle, Brian...
one of life's great journeys.
The greatest.
And journeys
are not to be feared.
We had fun, eh, Sister?
Oh, we certainly did.
And more to be had.
Come on.
The dancing awaits.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
♪ Move on, move ♪
♪ Move on Move ♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
♪ Move on, move ♪
♪ Move on Move ♪
♪ We're movin' on, movin' on ♪
♪ The journey's just begun ♪
♪ Get your groove on ♪
♪ Heading for the sun ♪
♪ Pump that pedal, sister ♪
♪ Don't ever drive alone ♪
♪ Right on, we're riding on ♪
♪ I'll get you back home ♪
♪ Movin' on, movin' on ♪
(CHEERING)
♪ Find your way ♪
♪ To the mountain top
that's waiting for you ♪
♪ Always lead with your heart ♪
♪ Move on, move ♪
♪ Move on Move ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Movin' on, movin' on ♪
(SHEEP BLEATS)
♪ Move ♪
♪ Movin' on, movin' on ♪
(♪♪♪)
♪ The journey's just begun ♪
♪ Get your groove on ♪
♪ Heading for the sun ♪
♪ Pump that pedal, sister ♪
♪ Don't ever drive alone ♪
♪ Right on, we're riding on ♪
♪ I'll get you back home ♪
♪ Find your way ♪
♪ To the mountain top
that's waiting for you ♪
♪ Always lead with your heart ♪
♪ Choose your path ♪
♪ To the ones who'll always
be there for you ♪
♪ Every end is a start ♪
(♪♪♪)
♪ Movin' on, we're movin' on ♪
♪ Move ♪
(♪♪♪)
♪ Vente ♪
♪ Episcopalis hominem ♪
(INDISTINCT LYRICS)
(♪♪♪)
♪ Pokarekare ana ♪
♪ Nga wai o Waiapu ♪
♪ Whiti atu koe e hine ♪
♪ Marino ana e ♪
♪ E hine e ♪
♪ Hoki mai ra ♪
♪ Ka mate ahau ♪
♪ I te aroha e ♪
♪ Tuhituhi taku reta ♪
♪ Tuku atu taku ringi ♪
♪ Kia kite to iwi ♪
♪ Raru raru ana e ♪
♪ E hine e ♪
♪ Hoki mai ra ♪
♪ Ka mate ahau ♪
♪ I te aroha e ♪
♪ E hine e ♪
♪ Hoki mai ra ♪
♪ Ka mate ahau ♪
♪ I te aroha e ♪